Fast & furry-ous
Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Road Chip is a family,
comedy, music film directed by Walt Becker.
Through a series of misunderstandings, Alvin, Simon and Theodore come to believe that Dave
is going to propose to his new girlfriend in New York City - and dump them.
They have three days to get to him and stop the proposal.
Dave, played by Jason Lee.
Alvin (voice), played by Justin Long.
Simon (voice), played by Matthew Gray Gubler.
Theodore (voice), played by Jesse McCartney.
Samantha, played by Kimberly Williams-Paisley.
Miles, played by Josh Green.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Road Chip is a 2015 American live-action animated jukebox musical
comedy film directed by Walt Becker and written by Randi Mayem Singer and Adam Sztykiel.
It is based on the characters Alvin and the
Chipmunks created by Ross Bagdasarian Sr.
and the Chipettes created by Janice Karman It is the fourth installment
in the live-action Alvin and the Chipmunks film series.
The ensemble cast includes Jason Lee, Tony Hale,
Kimberly Williams-Paisley and Josh Green.
Justin Long, Matthew Gray Gubler and Jesse McCartney all reprise their voice roles as the
Chipmunks, while Kaley Cuoco, Anna Faris and Christina Applegate voice the Chipettes.
The plot centers on the Chipmunks (Alvin, Simon, and Theodore) as they head to Miami after believing that
Dave Seville will propose to his girlfriend Samantha, who has a son who bullies the Chipmunks.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Road Chip was released in the United
States on December 18, 2015, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, and grossed $235 million
against a $90 million budget, becoming the lowest-grossing entry in the series.
The film explores themes of anthropomorphism, chipmunk,
hitchhiker, aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.